Guide to the Miguel A. Gandert Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- December 2006 Acquisition, 1986-2005; 5; 1.79; (20 boxes) + 7 broadsides oversize
  - Photographs
    - Bolivia and Mexico, Prints for a Fondation Henri Cartier-Bresson Award, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches.
      - Other Prints
        - Cosecha Trigo, Potosí, Bolivia, undated (Box 128 (Oversize))
        - Untitled photographs, undated; 2 (Box 128 (Oversize))
    - Gifts of the Land: New Mexico's Farm and Ranch Women
      This group of photographs consists of portraits of New Mexican farm and ranch women, circa 2001-2004, from an oral history project and planned traveling exhibition in collaboration with Glenda Balas.
      - Untitled photographs, 11 inches by 16 inches, circa 2001-2004; 3 (Box 128 (Oversize))
      - Untitled photographs, 16 inches by 20 inches, circa 2001-2004; 3 (Box 127 (Oversize))
    - Llano Estacado: An Island in the Sky
      Organized under two headings by print size: 14 inches by 20 inches and 16 inches by 20 inches.
      This group of photographs consists of work prints that depict the Llano Estacado (Spanish for palisaded plain), also known as the Staked Plain, a region in the Southwestern United States that encompasses parts of eastern New Mexico and northwestern Texas. The images relate to a project sponsored by the Southwest Center at Texas Tech University and were exhibited at the Houston Photofest in 2006. Images also appeared in Steve Bogener, William E. Tydeman, and Barry Holstun Lopez, Llano Estacado: An Island in the Sky (Lubbock: Texas Tech University Press, 2011).
      - 14 inches by 20 inches
        - Freight Train Traversing the Llano, undated (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - Ruins of Protestant Church on the Llano, undated (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - Windmill, undated (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - Untitled photographs, undated; 3 (Box 126 (Oversize))
      - 16 inches by 20 inches
        - Untitled photographs, undated; 5 (Box 127 (Oversize))
    - Miscellaneous Prints
      This group of photographs consists of portraits and scenes in New Mexico.
      - 11 inches by 14 inches
        - Bandelier National Monument, New Mexico, undated (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - The Montoya Sisters in Garden, undated (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - San Francisco de Asis Mission Church in Ranchos de Taos, New Mexico, undated (Box 126 (Oversize))
      - 16 inches by 20 inches
        - Cordova Weavers, undated (Box 127 (Oversize))
        - Girl in White Dress in front of a Zoo Cage, undated (Box 127 (Oversize))
        - Suspension, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 2004 (Box 127 (Oversize))
  - Video Recordings
    This subseries consists of short documentaries by and about Miguel Gandert.
    Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - The Indita or Plácida Romero. Enrique R. Lamadrid and Miguel Gandert (20061212-4487.0001), undated; 1 video disc (Box 129)
    - "On Assignment: Miguel Gandert," television program by New Mexico PBS, KNME-TV (20061212-4487.0002), undated; 1 video disc (Box 129)